# BRYAN NILSEN

646.221.1321 bryannilsen@gmail.com

https://github.com/BryanNilsen

www.linkedin.com/in/bryan-nilsen

www.bryannilsen.com

Full-Stack Software Developer, Graphic Artist, Problem Solver, Coach

# **About**

Enthusiastic team player, effective communicator, and creative thinker with a growing skillset in full-stack software development. I high-five often. Eager to learn as well as teach and motivate others. Not afraid to ask questions and go the extra mile to get the job done right.

Currently a Junior Instructor at Nashville Software School teaching Javascript / React on the client side and C# / ASP.Net Core as well as Python / Django on the server side. Advanced CSS skills.

Bachelor's Degree in Art and Design. Proficient with Adobe software suite including XD, UI/UX prototyping. Skilled painter with an eye for detail. Mediocre guitarist with a desire to shred.

Prior experience as a graphic artist and web designer, including nearly two years of international work.

Worked extensively as a stenographer, covering primarily civil litigation. Excellent communication skills. Managed tight deadlines and worked closely with attorneys in highly-confidential settings.

Just as comfortable in a suit and tie as I am in jeans and a rock t-shirt.

Transitioned out of the legal field to return to web development. I love solving problems with code and collaborating with others to achieve a common goal.

# **Education**

### **Nashville Software School**

Full-Stack Web Development Six-Month, Full-Time Bootcamp

**New York Career Institute** 

**AOS - Court Reporting** 

North Carolina State University College of Design

Bachelor of Arts - Art and Design

# **Coding Experience**

Junior Instructor - Software Developer - (see work history)

### **Full-Stack Software Developer**

Nashville Software School | Oct 2018 - Mar 2018

Full-time software development bootcamp focusing on full-stack web development fundamentals and problem solving, with final half of program executed in a simulated company environment with Scrum methodology.

- Built single-page client-side apps using React, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- · Developed server-side applications using Python, Django, and SQL
- Applied OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects reflecting real-world business problems
- Utilized source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Learned and applied JavaScript fundamentals leveraging DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- Implemented task automation with Grunt, linting with ESLint, and module bundling with Browserify
- Designed and wireframed applications using Adobe XD
- Planned applications by white boarding dependencies and building ERDs

# **Projects**

### MCA - Concert Tracking App - Server-Side Capstone

As a music lover and frequent concert-goer, I wanted an app where I could keep track of the concerts I've attended, view the setlists, add a rating, and store any photos or videos I took of the event all in one convenient place.

**MCA** is a responsive app that allows the user to search for concerts based on artist or venue, select the events they've attended and then add them to their list. Once added, the user can add their own rating, photos, and videos if they so desire.

MCA was written in **Python with Django** and utilizes the **Setlist.fm API**. **Github Repo:** https://github.com/BryanNilsen/MCA-MyConcertApp

## SwishList - Basketball Shot-Tracking App - Client-Side Capstone

An avid basketball player, I wanted an app to log shots from various court locations in order to track my accuracy, enabling me to focus on areas that needed improvement. Additionally, as a basketball coach, I felt this app would aid young players as well. By adding a leaderboard and leveling-up features, I believed the competitive element would encourage players to take more shots with the goal of improving their accuracy.

**Swishlist** is a responsive single-page basketball shot-tracking app that accomplishes the above needs and more. Players can log their workouts and shots using a dynamically-generated basketball court map built using custom CSS. Individual statistics are calculated and presented with leader-boards in addition to the user's profile and motivational quotes for added inspiration.

**Technologies: React, JSON Server, Custom CSS** 

Demo: https://swishlist-demo.herokuapp.com login email: test@test.com / password: test

Github Repo: https://github.com/BryanNilsen/Swishlist-React

# **BRYAN NILSEN**

646.221.1321

https://github.com/BryanNilsen

bryannilsen@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/bryan-nilsen

www.bryannilsen.com

# **Tech Skills**

### **LANGUAGES**

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- Python
- C#
- SQL

### FRAMEWORKS / LIBRARIES

- React
- Django
- ASP.Net Core
- Bootstrap
- Material UI
- Phaser

### MISC.

- Git Version Control
- · Webpack / Browserify
- Grunt

### **GRAPHICS SOFTWARE**

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- · Adobe XD
- · Adobe Sketch, Procreate

# **Volunteer**

### Head Coach Youth Basketball

2016-17

2017-18

2018-19

2019-20

### Assistant Coach Youth Football

2017-18

2018-19

2019-20

# **Work History**

### Junior Instructor - Software Developer

Nashville Software School | Apr 2018 - Present

- 12 months assisting lead instructor teaching client-side software development concepts including HTML, CSS, GIT version control, JavaScript and React (hooks)
- 3 months assisting lead instructor teaching server-side technologies including C#, ASP.Net Core, and SOL Server
- Acted as product manager and Scrum leader during group projects, leading sprint planning, daily stand-ups, and sprint retros utilizing Agile methodologies
- Coached students through troubleshooting and debugging techniques
- Contributed to course curriculum
- Assisted admissions team in conducting interviews of prospective students
- Transitioned to work remote via Zoom, providing lectures and code debugging

### **Director of Business Development / Client Relations**

Alpha Reporting Corporation | Oct 2016 - Sep 2018 | Nashville, TN

- Managed local Nashville branch of court reporting firm
- · Communicated directly with clients to handle requests and/or concerns
- Maintained local office, supplies, computer equipment, and peripherals
- Coordinated and performed videoconference equipment tests for depositions
- Presented company information at industry conferences
- · Created text copy and visual content for social media campaign
- · Face-to-Face sales visits with existing and potential clients

### Court Reporter / Stenographer - Independent Contractor

Various Court Reporting Agencies | Jul 2004 - Sep 2016 - New York, NY

- · Worked directly with attorneys and judges in confidential settings
- Transcribed and produced verbatim transcripts of legal testimony for depositions, hearings, arbitrations, and various court matters
- · Provided instant, real-time transcripts to attorneys during live testimony
- Frequently requested to cover complex and sensitive assignments
- · Covered presidential speeches at the United Nations and other venues in NYC
- · Consistently met client transcript delivery deadlines
- Managed and organized work schedule and backlog with multiple reporting firms
- Performed all duties in accordance with the NCRA Code of Professional Ethics

# Freelance Graphic Designer / Web Developer

The Coastal Group / Redscope LLC | Apr 2002 - Dec 2002 - New York City

- · Website design, wireframing, and coding HTML, CSS
- Utilized QuarkXpress and inDesign for typography and content layout
- Prepared product images for web and print catalog: resizing, silhouetting

# **Graphic Artist / Engraving Consultant / Web Developer**

Precision Design Partners / The Ardenza Group | 1999 – 2001 - Dublin, Ireland

- Advised on equipment setup and instructed proper glass and crystal engraving techniques on-site at Waterford Crystal location
- · Created custom artwork by hand and with image editing software
- Networked local office computers and peripherals
- · Designed, wireframed, and built websites for local Irish businesses
- · HTML, CSS, Flash with Actionscript

# **Graphic Artist**

Rayzist Photomask, Inc | Mar 1998 - Jul 1999 - Vista, CA

- Developed custom artwork for glass and crystal engraving process
- · Interacted directly with clients to understand needs and deliver desired results
- · Taught monthly seminars on graphic software, engraving process and techniques